Finding Aid for Department of Journalism (University of Michigan) research papers, 1967-1978
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Student Papers, Fall 1975
  - Jacknow, Lisa.
    - "Detroit Newspaper Coverage of the United Automobile Workers, 1937" (Box 2)
      [146]
  - Mansfield, Doris.
    - "The Osceola County Seat War of 1891" (Box 2)
  - Miller, Christine.
    - "General Motors and the Flint Journal vs. the U.A.W.-C.I.O" (Box 2)
      [146a]
  - Pantaleo, Nancy.
    - "Campaign Coverage in the Michigan AFL-CIO News, 1952 and 1960" (Box 2)
      [147]
  - Schmitz, Crystal. Untitled. (Box 2)
  - Sheiner, E. Susan.
    - "Press Coverage of the Equal Suffrage Amendment in Michigan, 1918" (Box 2)
      [148]
  - Short, Douglas L.
    - "The Changes in Content and Format of the Gladwin County Record" (Box 2)
      [149]
  - Stubbs, Jim.
    - "The Detroit News and the Detroit Free Press and the Conflict in Cuba" (Box 2)
      [150]
  - Turque, Bill.
    - "The Detroit Free Press and the Detroit Evening News: Two Stories of a President's Death" (Box 2)
      [152]
  - Wrightman, Arthur.
    - "Overstepping the Wires or How the Associated Press Twisted the Michigan Copper Strike" (Box 2)
      [153]
  - Zick, John.
    - "The Press and Politics: Progressivism in Michigan" (Box 2)
      [154]
- Student Papers, Fall 1976
  - Drahos, Steve.
    - "Factors Affecting Circulation of the Detroit Free Press and the Detroit News" (Box 2)
      [155]
  - Erickson, Marsha.
    - " The Lapeer County Press, 1846-1976: The Evolution of a Rural Weekly" (Box 2)
      [156]
  - Kopanski, Kathryn M.
    - "A Biography of Karl Detzer of Leland, Michigan" (Box 2)
      [157]
  - Moragne, Linda.
    - "An Analysis of the Michigan Chronicle" (Box 2)
      [158]
  - Pukszta, Ron.
    - "The Changing Face of Advertising in the Late 1800s and Its Implications as an Economic Indicator" (Box 2)
  - Pyder, Thomas.
    - "The Brown Bomber in Black and White" (Box 2)
      [169]
- Student Papers, Winter 1978
  - Berry, Camille.
    - "The Anatomy of the Michigan Suffragist" (Box 2)
      [161]
  - Cole, Steven R.
    - "The Detroit News, The Detroit Free Press, The Detroit Times and The Ferguson-O'Hara Grand Jury" (Box 2)
      [162]
  - Godfrey, Christopher.
    - "An Interview with Bob Ufer" (Box 2)
      [162a]
  - Henderson, Miriam.
    - " Detroit Free Press Coverage of the Stock Market Crash, October-November, 1929" (Box 2)
      [163]
  - Johnson, Jesse.
    - "An Analysis of the Gogebic Explorer" (Box 2)
      [164]
  - Katsarelas, Nicholas G.
    - "The 1924 Detroit Free Press: A Vivid Reflection of an Era" (Box 2)
      [165]
  - Meadows, Deborah R.
    - " The Christian Journal: Reflection of a People" (Box 2)
      [166]
  - Miller, Brian.
    - "American Correspondents' Coverage of the Battle of Britain" (Box 2)
      [167]
  - O'Donnell, Joseph W.
    - "Facts in Controversy:. A Survey of Reporting by the Detroit News of the Truman-MacArthur Controversy" (Box 2)
      [168]
  - Treer, Gary.
    - "Early Advertisements in Ann Arbor Newspapers" (Box 2)
  - Tregembo, Michelle.
    - "A Study of the Keweenaw Miner, January through March 1915" (Box 2)
      [170]
  - Wesley, Olivia T.
    - " The Plaindealer, 1883-1893" (Box 2)
      [171]
- Student Papers, Fall 1986
  - Ruehr, Ruthann R.
    - "An Analysis of Local Newspaper Coverage of the House Un-American Activities Committee Actions Involving the University of Michigan" (Box 2)
      [172]
- Student Papers, Fall 1992
  - Balconi, Jean Marie.
    - "Fire, Death and Crime: The Localization of Newspaper Coverage" (Box 2)
      [173]
Topical Index
The numbers in this index refer to the number in brackets [] following each thesis.
Adrian (Mich.) -- Newspapers
52, 57, 90
Adrian Daily Times and Expositor
140
Adrian Telegram (newspaper)
57
Advertising
159, 169
AFL-CIO News
147
Ann Arbor (Mich.)
37, 38, 76
Ann Arbor (Mich.) -- Newspapers
46, 67, 76, 101, 108, 110
Ann Arbor Courier (newspaper)
38
Ann Arbor Register
122, 159
Ann Arbor Sun (newspaper)
53, 54
Antisemitism
30, 60
Applegate, Harriet Marie
52
Associated Press, Inc.
153
Auburn (Mich.)
77
Banks and Banking
77
Baseball
74
Battle Creek Enquirer and News
134
Bay City Times
77
Bay County (Mich.)
1
Beal, Junius Emery, 1860-1942
132
Blacks in Michigan
2, 14, 15, 20, 117
Booth, George Gough, 1864-1949
61, 94
Bunyan, Paul (Legendary character)
86
CIO News
11
Cheboygan (Mich.)
49
Cheboygan Tribune
49
Chicanos in Michigan
98
The Christian Journal
166
Civil Rights News
78
Civil War
40
Clare (Mich.)
72
Coffman, Al
139
Cook, Marshall L, 1858-1955
136
Cook, William Randolph, 1866-1946
136
Corselius, George, 1806-1849
101
Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979
32, 51, 59, 91, 99, 114, 115
Crime and criminals
173
Crockett, George W.
107
The Cross and the Flag (magazine)
60
Dearborn (Mich.) -- Newspapers
118
The Dearborn Independent (newspaper)
30, 43, 50
Depression, 1929-1938
51, 102
Detroit (Mich.) -- Newspapers
10, 16, 17, 19, 62, 69, 70, 78, 81, 88, 102, 104, 114
Detroit Free Press
35, 36, 40, 44, 64, 74
Detroit Gazette
34
Detroit Labor News
145
Detroit News
64, 66, 68
The Detroit Times
39
Detroit Post and Tribune
47
Die Washtenaw Post
108
Detzer, Karl William, 1891-
157
Dutch in Michigan
166
Election of 1896
194
Election of 1951
147
Election of 1960
147
Emancipation Proclamation
35
Evart Review (newspaper)
146
The Fifth Estate (newspaper)
97
Flint (Mich.)
3
Flint Journal
146a
Ford, Henry, 1863-1947
30, 31, 43, 50
Forest fires
173
Foster, Theodore, 1812-1865
45
Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881
173
Genesee County (Mich.)
22
Gladwin County Record (newspaper)
150,173
Gogebic County (Mich.)
7
Gogebic Explorer (newspaper)
7, 55, 75
Grand Rapids (Mich.)
13
Grand Rapids (Mich.) -- Newspapers
56, 61
Grand Rapids Press
61, 105
The Hastings Banner
6, 95
Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951
63
Hillsdale Gazette
142
Hillsdale Whig Standard (newspaper)
142
Hogan, Henry M., Jr.
12
Howard City Record (newspaper)
148
Huron County (Mich.)
21
Huron Daily Tribune
79, 80
Inkster (Mich.)
20
Journalists
10
The Keweenaw Miner (newspaper)
170
Labor
62, 63
Lapeer County (Mich.)
21, 85
Lapeer County Press (newspaper)
156
Lathers, Swift
58
Livingston County (Mich.)
28
Livingston County (Mich.) -- Newspapers
111
Louis, Joe, 1914-1981
96
Mackinac bridge
128
Macomb County (Mich.)
29
Marshall (Mich.)
41
McKinley, William, Pres. U.S., 1843-1901.
152
Mears Newz
58
Michigan Argus
122, 133, 169
Michigan Chronicle
2
Michigan Daily
82, 106
Michigan Suffragist (newspaper)
161
The Michigan Union (newspaper)
119
Michigan Whig
37
Midland (Mich.)
173
Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954
9, 103
Mt. Clemens (Mich.)
24
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949
39
Nader, Ralph, 1934-
5
Negroes in Michigan
158,171
Newsboys
105
Niles (Mich.) -- Newspapers
116
Nosotros (newspaper)
98
Oakland County (Mich.)
25
Osborn, Chase Salmon, 1860-1949
144
Osceola County Democrat
146
Ontonagon County (Mich.)
7
Ontonagon Herald
7
Penninsular Courier and Family Visitant (Ann Arbor)
122
Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.
134a
Photography, Journalism
125
The Plaindealer (newspaper)
117
Progressivism (U.S. politics)
154
Radio broadcasting
15, 17, 20, 32, 68, 71, 72, 100, 112
Radulovich, Milo
93
Railroads
120
Reed City Weekly Clarion
146
Richard, Gabriel, 1767-1832.
141
Riots -- Detroit (Mich.), 1967
8, 65
Royal Oak Daily Tribune
103
Saginaw County (Mich.)
26
Saginaw News
173
St. Clair County (Mich.)
24
Sanilac County (Mich.)
21
Sault Sainte Marie News
144
Shiawasee County (Mich.)
23
Signal of Liberty
45, 87
Slavery and anti-slavery movements
46, 87
Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth, 1898-1976
60
Social Justice (newspaper)
91, 99
Social life and customs, 1891-1900
126
Social life and customs, 1921-1930
165
Social life and customs, 1941-1950
126
Social life and customs, 1961-1970
126
Spanish-American War
56, 81
The Spinal Column (newspaper)
107
Sports journalism
130,135,139, 162a
Storey, Wilbur Fisk, 1819-1884
48
Strikes and lockouts
3, 57, 69
Television broadcasting
15, 29
Temperance
84, 119
Tuscola County (Mich.)
21
Ufer, Robert Pormann, 1920-
162a
United Automobile, Aircraft and Agricultural Implement Workers of America.
145
University of Michigan -- History
109
University of Michigan -- Radio Broadcasting
112
University of Michigan -- Student publications
18, 82, 106
Upper Peninsula (Michigan)
55, 75, 120
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951
33
W. C. H. B. (radio station), Inkster
20
W. P. A. G. (radio station), Ann Arbor
100
Washtenaw County (Mich.) -- Newspapers
27
Washtenaw Whig (newspaper)
133
Western Emigrant (newspaper)
101, 110
Western Statesman (newspaper)
41
Women history
52, 64, 66, 67, 73, 109
Women's Christian Temperance Union
119
World War, 1914-1918
6, 42, 44, 108
World war, 1939-1945
167
Academic Freedom
172
Michigan. University-Faculty
172
U.S. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.
172